Minna Lederman Daniel Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Subject Files (General Subjects), (47 folders) (Boxes 13-16)
  - Modern Music Archives at Library of Congress. Photographs - Guides (Box-folder 15/7)
  - Modern Music Archives at Library of Congress. Photographs - Library of Congress Exhibition (1975) (Box-folder 15/8)
  - Modern Music Archives at Library of Congress. Photographs - Negatives (Box-folder 15/9)
  - Modern Music Archives at Library of Congress. Photographs - Scene designs (Box-folder 15/10)
  - Modern Music Archives at Library of Congress. Press releases - Library of Congress Exhibition (1975) (Box-folder 15/11)
  - Modern Music Archives at Library of Congress. Writings (Lederman): Biographical sketches (Box-folder 15/12)
  - Modern Music Archives at Library of Congress. Writings (Lederman): "The Files of Modern Music Correspondence" [miscellaneous writings]; [Promotional writings]; "Modern Music 1924-1946: Footnotes to Its History" (Box-folder 15/13)
  - Music criticism. Articles: "On Being Tasteless," 1982 (William Brooks); "From a Composer's Notebook," 1929 (Aaron Copland); [Several newspaper articles], (Kyle Gann); "Expanding Century," 1979 (David Hamilton); [Several newspaper articles], (Donal Henahan); "Reporter in Europe," 1980 (Jane Kramer); "Little Magazines and Music Criticism," 1946 (Minna Lederman); [Several newspaper articles], (John Rockwell); "Modern Music in Retrospect," 1964 (Eric Salzman); [Several newspaper articles], (Harold Schonberg) (Box-folder 16/1)
  - Music criticism. Clippings (Box-folder 16/2)
  - Music criticism. Correspondence: Lederman (1979); H. Wiley Hitchcock (1979) (Box-folder 16/3)
  - Music criticism. Clippings (Box-folder 16/4)
  - Music press. Clippings (Box-folder 16/5)
  - Possible future projects. Army notes, 1943-1944, Army town, Anniston, AL; "Summer People - a Maine idyll," Correspondence: 1941-1942, other related materials; "Sunken Living-Room" (Box-folder 16/6)
  - Publishers and publishing. Clippings (Box-folder 16/7)
  - Publishers and publishing. Correspondence: Bea Friedland, Da Capo Press (1979-1984); Peter Garland, Soundings (1980); Jeffrey Miller, Cadmus Editions (1979); Helen A. Stephenson, Author's Guild, Inc. (1980-1981) (Box-folder 16/8)
- Magazines, (10 folders) (Box 17)
  Includes complete magazines, containing articles written by Minna Lederman.
  Arranged alphabetically by title of publication.
  - Lederman, Minna. "Composers in Revolt," The Nation 146, no. 7 (1938 Feb. 12) (Box-folder 17/1)
  - Lederman, Minna. "Music and Monopoly," The Nation 151, no. 126 (1940 Dec. 28) (Box-folder 17/2)
  - Lederman, Minna. "France's Turncoat Artists," The Nation 155, no. 9 (1942 Aug. 29) (Box-folder 17/3)
  - Lederman, Minna. "Composer Tells All," The New Republic 102, no. 13 (1940 Mar. 25) (Review of The State of Music by Virgil Thomson) (Box-folder 17/4)
  - Lederman, Minna. [Book review] The Saturday Review of Literature 29, no. 47 (1946 Nov. 23) (Review of A House in Bali by Colin McPhee) (Box-folder 17/5)
  - Lederman, Minna. "Memories of Marc Blitzstein, Music's Angry Man," Show 4, no. 6 (1964 June) (copy 1) (Box-folder 17/6)
  - Lederman, Minna. "Memories of Marc Blitzstein, Music's Angry Man," Show 4, no. 6 (1964 June) (copy 2) (Box-folder 17/7)
  - Lederman, Minna. "Memories of Marc Blitzstein, Music's Angry Man," Show 4, no. 6 (1964 June) (copy 3) (Box-folder 17/8)
  - Lederman, Minna. "American Future: The Music Theatre," U.S. Lines: Paris Review (undated) (Box-folder 17/9)
  - Lederman, Minna. "School Declares an Extra Dividend," Woman's Home Companion (1937 Nov.) (Box-folder 17/10)
- Personal Papers of Minna Lederman Daniel and other Daniel Family Members, (28 folders) (Boxes 18-20)
  Contains correspondence, financial and legal papers, miscellaneous writings, speeches, and family photographs.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material, and chronologically therein.
  - Address/Telephone books, (2) (Box-folder 18/1)
  - Appointment calendars: 1987, 1989, 1990, 1992, 1993, (5) (Box-folder 18/2)
  - Household furniture and furnishings papers, Sept. 1967 (Box-folder 18/3)
  - Autobiographical notes (Box-folder 18/4)
  - Correspondence: Family (1966-1991) (Box-folder 18/5)
  - Correspondence: Ferncliff Cemetery (1952-1978); related papers (Box-folder 18/6)
  - Correspondence: Re. Mell Daniel's paintings (1975-1977); related papers (Box-folder 18/7)
  - Legal papers: Appraisal papers (furniture/furnishings), Dec. 1975 (Box-folder 18/8)
  - Legal papers: Birth certificates; Marriage certificate; Passport; Handgun receipt (Box-folder 18/9)
  - Legal papers: Power of Attorney papers 1981; 1986-1987 (Box-folder 18/10)
  - Legal papers: Trust papers, May 1981 (Box-folder 18/11)
  - Legal papers: Wills, Nov. 22, 1964 (Mell Daniel); Oct. 16, 1975; Mar. 21, 1981 (Minna Lederman Daniel); related correspondence (1978-1981) (Box-folder 18/12)
  - Photographs: Vassar College (1914), (12 photographs) (Box-folder 19/1)
  - Photographs: Family photographs; negatives (Box-folder 19/2)
  - Photographs: Mell Daniel World War II photographs; Mell Daniel (early); Wedding photographs of Minna and Mell Daniel (1934) (Box-folder 19/3)
  - Travel: Germany, 1967 - brochure; postcards; Holland, 1967 - maps; postcards (Box-folder 20/1)
  - Travel: Israel 1968 - brochures; clippings; correspondence; notes; postcards (Box-folder 20/2)
  - Travel: Israel - Greece - Holland, 1968: papers (Box-folder 20/3)
  - Travel: Riga, Latvia, 1967 - brochures; postcards (Box-folder 20/4)
  - Travel: Rome, Italy, (undated) - postcards (Box-folder 20/5)
  - Travel: U.S.S.R., 1967 - art catalog; brochures; clippings; correspondence; maps; miscellaneus papers; notes (Box-folder 20/6)
  - Travel: U.S.S.R., 1967 - postcards; suggestions/travel tips sheets (Box-folder 20/7)
  - Writings: (Lederman): Dance Forum, Y.W.H.A., Nov. 1946 [Speech] (Box-folder 20/8)
  - Writings (Lederman): "The Cause of Modern Music From the Point of View of the Editor of Modern Music," MacDowell Club of New York City Dinner, Nov. 27, 1927 [Speech] (Box-folder 20/9)
  - Writings (Lederman): Miscellaneous writings (Box-folder 20/10)
  - Writings (Lederman): NBC [Unknown program] (radio broadcast) March 1, 1935 [Speech delivered by Lederman] (Box-folder 20/11)
  - Writings (Lederman): NBC Program of League of Composers (radio broadcast) April 16, 1936 [Speech] (Box-folder 20/12)
  - Writings (Lederman): "Modern Music as the Editor Thinks of It," Sorosis Social Day, Jan. 1928 [Speech] (Box-folder 20/13)
Appendix: Index of Personal Names
Albee, Edward
Anderson, Laurie
Ashbery, John
Balanchine, George
Barber, Samuel
Berger, Arthur
Bernier, Rosamond
Bernstein, Leonard
Blitzstein, Marc
Boulanger, Nadia
Boulez, Pierre
Bowles, Paul
Cage, John
Caltabiano, Ronald
Carter, Elliott
Chanler, Theodore
Chávez, Carlos
Copland, Aaron
Cowell, Henry
Craft, Robert
Crumb, George
Cunningham, Merce
Daniel, Mell
Daniel, Minna Lederman
Darrell, R. D.
Denby, Edwin
Einhorn, Nathan R.
Foss, Lukas
Friedland, Bea
Frueh, Alfred
Garland, Peter
Gershwin, George
Glass, Philip
Haggin, B. H.
Haieff, Alexei
Harris, Roy
Hitchcock, H. Wiley
Ives, Charles
Ives, Harmony
Jacobs, Paul
Kirstein, Lincoln
Kominski, John J.
Lederman, Minna
Lichtenwanger, William
Lott, R. Allen
McPhee, Colin
Magriel, Paul
Mehta, Zubin
Milhaud, Darius
Miller, Jeffrey
Moore, Douglas
Morton, Lawrence
Moseley, Carlos
Nabokov, Nicolas
Nancarrow, Conlon
Oja, Carol J.
Perlis, Vivian
Peyser, Joan
Reich, Steve
Reis, Clare R.
Rieti, Vittorio
Rorem, Ned
Ruggles, Carl
Sacher, Paul
Satie, Erik
Schiff, David
Schoenberg, Arnold
Schuman, William
Sessions, Roger
Shapero, Harold
Shirley, Wayne
Siegmeister, Elie
Sondheim, Stephen
Stephenson, Helen A.
Stockhausen, Karlheinz
Stravinsky, Igor
Thompson, Tazewell
Thomson, Virgil
Tommasini, Anthony
Tucker, Mark
Varèse, Louise
Walker, David
Waters, Ed
Wuorinen, Charles
Young, La Monte